Kirill Shaplyko

Email: k.shaplyko@gmail.com

Skype: k.shaplyko Phone: +375 336 37 60 90

Github: Baltazore

LinkedIn: Kirill Shaplyko Twitter: _baltazore Address: Minsk, Belarus

OVERVIEW

I am a web developer with extensive knowledge and experience in Ruby and JavaScript. My most recent experience has been as a full stack web developer at mobile advertising startup.

You can find some of my work on Github profile. My recent technological interests and passions include the EmberJS, AngularJS, and ReactJS front-end frameworks, and experimenting with writing back-end services in Elixir.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Consulting

Software Developer 06.2015 - current, Remote

- ► Refactoring and optimizing large legacy codebases.
- Communicating with clients and gathering requirements.
- ► Project planning, creating roadmaps.
- Teaching and mentoring.
- ► Working on the deployments tasks.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, AWS, Heroku, EmberJS, AngularJS.

GameHouse

Software Developer, 10.2013 - 05.2015, Remote

- ► Full stack engineer responsible for development application using Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, MongoDB, Redis, AngularJS.
- Working on the deployments tasks. Learning Ansible and Docker for building container based hosts.
- Developing the advertisement platform for the mobile devices.
- Brainstorm and prototype the new approach for some parts of the application.
- Writing specs and cucumber scenarios for integration tests for our API endpoints.

RubyRoid Labs

Software Developer, 09.2013 - 12.2014, Remote

- ► Full stack engineer responsible for development application using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Redis, AngularJS, Elasticsearch.
- ► Document generation system. The project includes document generation, task management for Police Department, Hospitals, ect.

Itransition

Ruby on Rails Developer, 08.2012 - 09.2013, Minsk, Belarus

► Mobile advertising platform for back-end, front-end and mobile clients API for iOS and Android. The project is intended to increase sales for businesses by providing discounts.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Redis, Sidekiq, Faye, Pushover.

► Online auction system. Full auction workflow support (from creating to send notification about winnign beds). Dealing with admin panel, server back-end for real-time bid system.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Redis, MySQL, Faye, MongoDB, Rescue

► Social Media Aggregation System. It aggregates data by keywords from Facebook, Twitter, Sysomos (15+ servises), Google News, Google Blogs, Youtube, Google Images and Vocus (Print media and Blogspot). Dealing with main aggregation gateways, alert system (sms, email), report system (pdf, plain text, html).

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Facebook API, Twitter API, Klout API, Elasticsearch

EDUCATION

Belarussian State of Informatics and Radioelectronics

B.S. in Computer Science, May 2014

TECHNOLOGY FOCUS

Programming Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, Elixir

Web Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Sintra, Node.js, Phoenix

Frontend Web Frameworks: AngularJS, EmberJS

DevOps: AWS (EC2, S3, Route53), Heroku, Chef, Ansible, Capistrano

Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu, CoreOS), *Mac OS X*

Programming Editors/IDEs: vim, emacs, tmux **Source Code Control:** *Git*, Mercurial, Subversion

Databases: PostgreSQL 8/9, MySQL 4/5, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch

Other technologies: AMQP (RabbitMQ), Resque, Sidekiq